"Previously on
The Mentalist..."
This is my date outfit.
Is this your first date? I mean
um, since your wife died.
Do I seem outta practice?
Red John
if you're listening to us now
I urge you to reach out
and get help.
You can change.
"What the hell are you thinking?"
"Don't you understand
who you're dealing with?"
- Red John is not coming after me.
- Are you blind?
You've done exactly what I did
and he killed my wife and child.
Kristina?
"Red John could've gotten
in and taken her"
"or maybe
he lured her out somehow."
"Tiger, tiger burning bright"
"in the forests of the night"
"what immortal hand or eye
could frame thy fearful symmetry?"
I almost forgot. Kristina would
want me to send her love.
- You can't park there.
- Sure, I can.
Look.
- There you are.
- Here I am. Good morning.
Why so glum?
This is Harvey Dublin.
That's his chauffeur Peter Russo
with three bullets in him.
That's his car.
Mr. Dublin's gone.
Abducted, it looks like.
- Harvey Dublin?
- Big-time statehouse lobbyist
lawyer, kingmaker.
- Famous and well-connected.
- Ah, the evil twins.
Brass and media are gonna be
all over us like suckerfish.
Oh, why don't we just give it
to the FBI? They love that stuff.
Oh, I wish. Too late.
The new boss is here doing
on-cameras. It's our baby.
New boss?
I thought Hightower was boss.
The boss of Hightower.
The director of the entire division.
I told you about him last week.
Your memory's going.
My memory is a mighty fortress, Lisbon
from which no fact
ever escapes once committed.
Now when you tell me
boring things
I set 'em free immediately.
Saves overcrowding.
Harvey Dublin is missing.
It looks like a kidnapping
presumably for ransom
but we can't be sure at present.
We shall have to await
further developments.
Harvey is a pillar of this city
one of the good guys.
We are all praying
for his safety.
Thank you.
Idiot.
You and your snap judgments.
What is he supposed to say?
Why does he have to say anything?
What's your take on this?
Hmm.
I don't know.
Eh, I think I'll give this one a miss.
A miss?
What do you mean "a miss"?
I just feel this one
is not for me.
I'll catch the next one.
I-I-I promise.
I don't understand.
You're not gonna...
- Agent Lisbon, I believe? And Mr. Jane?
- Yes. Hi.
Director Bertram
will speak to you now.
We're on a super tight schedule.
He appreciates facts and brevity.
Okay?
- Agent Lisbon.
- Yes, sir, Director Bertram.
And you must be our boy wonder
Patrick Jane.
I've heard a lotta good things
about you.
Hi. Nice to meet you, sir.
Now I want this resolved
A.S.A.P.
Whatever it takes. The heck
with overtime restrictions.
You do the hours
I'll find the funding.
We are all in this together
as one.
- That's what I'm all about.
- Oh, we are on it, sir.
Uh, yeah, I won't be working
this particular case
but I-I do like what you said.
We're all in this together as one.
Mao Tse Tung, right?
Now hold your horses there, Buster.
What do you mean you won't
be working on this one?
Well, statehouse lobbyist
abductions...
it's, uh, not really
my cup of tea.
Well, that's... that's kind of
unprofessional, don't you think?
I guess, but I'm not actually
a professional.
Question for you.
W-why are you here?
Aside from the cameras.
Oh, what do you mean
"aside from the cameras"?
Public perception
is an important tool.
Mm.
Tool.
- You just put your hand on me.
- No.
- I mean, yes, but...
- Yes, you did. Don't ever do that again.
Or else what?
You ever smell a dead mouse?
Do you remember that smell?
Yes.
Well, I just now put a dead mouse
in your jacket pocket.
And no matter how many times
you clean that jacket
you'll always smell that dead mouse
and you'll remember that you should
never have put your hand on me.
You son of a bitch.
It's actually just a wadded up napkin
but, uh, has the same
psychological effect.
Human mind is funny that way.
Good to meet you, sir.
Sorry, Lisbon.
He had a rough summer.
"Rigsby and Van Pelt are canvassing
the area around the abduction site."
Cho's with Mrs. Dublin
waiting for a ransom demand
and tech services
are up and running.
Well, this is a Scary one.
Lots of attention.
Keep Molly in public affairs
apprised of any good stuff
we can feed the media
keep them on our side
and don't make any mistakes.
No, ma'am.
How's Jane?
The same.
You think he's in danger
of cracking up?
No.
I mean, no. Well, I don't think so.
I think he'll be fine.
That's not very convincing, Lisbon.
What he's been through
would break anyone.
He's not gonna crack up.
I think some time off
will do him good, though.
Yeah, well, no can do.
Bertram wants him
on the Dublin case.
- After Jane was so rude to him?
- Bertram's all bottom line.
He won't let
personal issues intrude.
Jane's the best asset we have
and Bertram knows that.
- But Jane doesn't wanna be on the case.
- Change his mind.
I'm not gonna tell Bertram
we can't control our own people.
I have an idea
as to how to persuade him
but it's kind of unethical.
I don't wanna know.
- Where's Jane?
- He's upstairs.
Thanks.
Jane?
Come in.
Hey.
Nice place.
Yeah. Yeah, I like
the view and the quiet.
And what are you doing
with all the quiet?
Just thinking.
Jane, you have to stop
blaming yourself.
If Red John took Kristina Frye
it's not your...
- There's no "if", he took her.
- If he did, you can't blame yourself.
Besides, what good is it
to sit up here
scribbling in your book?
You're not gonna find her that way.
I'm not gonna change my mind.
I don't wanna work the Dublin case.
That's fine. It's a done deal.
I understand.
It'd be good for you
to have a break.
Listen, on a completely other subject
I need a personal favor.
I'd like you to come
and meet someone.
Who?
- I can't tell.
- Why not?
I promise it has nothing to do
with Harvey Dublin.
You're trying to play me somehow
convince me
to change my mind.
- No.
- Yes, you are.
And I guess I owe you a shot.
But it's not gonna work
whatever it is.
Hey, Cho, how's it goin'
with Mrs. Dublin?
Nothing so far. When's somebody
coming to relieve me here?
Why? What's the problem?
Nothing. I'll call if we get
any developments.
- What is it? Is it Harvey?
- No, ma'am.
Oh, my God!
I am gonna explode!
I can't stand it!
I can't take it!
I swear to God!
Why, Kimball?
Why am I being punished?
I'm a good person.
Yes, ma'am.
Stop calling me ma'am!
I'm not your grandmother.
How old do you think I am
anyway?
48, 49.
- I get the picture.
- Do you?
Yeah, Dublin's driver...
the dead guy, Pete Russo, right?
He has family.
He wasn't wearing
a wedding ring, so, uh...
We're about to meet a, uh...
Yes. Exactly.
Yes, who are you?
Nadine, I'm Agent Lisbon
with the CBI.
We spoke on the phone.
This is Patrick Jane.
Hi. You're, uh,
Pete Russo's daughter?
Uh, yeah.
- Hello?
- They're police.
- Oh, okay.
- This is my mom.
Patricia.
And this is Keith, my stepdad.
Hi. Um...
Please come in.
Miss Lisbon says you're the best
detective in California.
She says if anybody can find
who killed my father, you can.
I just have to say
I didn't think you would stoop
to such crude manipulation.
I don't understand.
Inside joke. I'm sorry.
Uh, I will find who killed your father
and abducted Mr. Dublin.
An inside joke?
Her father is dead.
Murdered.
You're making jokes?
Yes, uh, it's a fault of mine.
Uh, what it is, the joke?
Uh, I have a... I have a lot
on my mind right now.
Uh, I didn't really wanna come
to work today
but my good friend and colleague
Agent Lisbon
tricked me into meeting you
knowing that I couldn't refuse you
because you're the age
my daughter would be
if she were still alive
if she hadn't been murdered.
- Oh, goodness.
- Murdered by a man named Red John
whom I met with recently.
He saved my life
and abducted a friend of mine.
Long story.
Hence, many things on my mind.
That's not a very funny joke.
Hmm.
What happened to your friend?
Still missing.
Uh, please, tell us about your father.
He was a good person.
He was... funny and...
And generous.
And I could talk to him about
anything, and he would listen.
Yes, he could be charming.
He had his ways.
- What kinda ways?
- He had a temper.
That he did.
I mean, his heart was
in the right place, you know?
Whatever his faults
he didn't deserve to die this way.
Really, I'm impressed.
You... you played me like a fish
and... and you lied to me.
I kinda did, didn't I? Sorry.
No, I'm glad to see you're finally
learning a few things.
Of course, uh, now I shall have
my revenge.
What do you mean?
Don't worry.
We're not here about drugs.
We're here about the killing
the other night.
Ah, yeah, yeah.
I heard about that.
Kidnapped a man, huh?
That's too bad.
Local beat cops say you guys
do business under that bridge.
Yeah, look, the local beat cops
are nice guys, but they're outta touch.
We don't do business under that bridge.
The hos... they got dibs.
You're gonna wanna talk
to the ladies over on Fremont.
- All right. Thanks.
- Yeah, no worries.
Hey, hey, Red.
You... you ever date
a hustler before?
Not so far!
What? I'm kidding.
- Thank you.
- Yeah. Okay.
Good to know.
Good afternoon. Reid Colman.
I'm Mr. Dublin's personal lawyer.
Glad to see you people.
You made any progress?
Early days, Mr. Colman.
You'll, uh, need to talk to me, yes?
Now's a good time.
I have ten minutes or so.
If you'll come this way
we can use the conference room.
Uh, just a moment.
What's your name?
- Marjorie.
That's a very nice name. I'd like
to speak to Marjorie first, thanks.
Uh, we will need to speak
to you in due course, sir.
I'll, uh, try and fit you in later.
Prostitutes? No. No.
Mr. Dublin was not
that sort of man at all.
The alleyway
from which he was abducted
was used by prostitutes
and it was nowhere near
Mr. Dublin's regular route.
I have been Mr. Dublin's personal
secretary for ten years
and I can tell you
without a shadow of a doubt
that he is the most decent
caring, clean, generous human being
that anyone could hope
to meet.
We wanna bring him back
safely, Marjorie.
We need to know everything.
Usually I can get ahold
of him at any time.
His work demands it
but once in a while
he'd disappear for an hour or so
no... no answer from him
or his driver.
- How often was that?
- Every couple of weeks.
A regular date right around
the time he was abducted, yes?
And what did you think
he might be doing?
Mistress, I thought
but not this.
Men have needs.
I understand that.
Please, you'll find him, won't you?
You'll find him?
Marjorie, uh, I have to tell you
it's very likely
that he's already dead.
Whoa. Wait a minute.
- We don't know that.
- It's a hunch that I have
and if I'm right
it's a blessing for you.
Unrequited love
is a terrible thing.
You have to find yourself a man
that will love you back.
You're a good woman.
You deserve it. Think about that.
So this was done by someone
who knew about Dublin's routine...
someone very close.
Wh-why did you say
he was dead?
Because he is. He's dead
and it's not a kidnapping.
Give me a reason.
I'll bet you all the tea in China.
- That is not a reason.
- I'll give you good odds.
Hey.
Hey. Ransom demand
came through.
How much?
All right.
We're on our way.
A million dollars
for the safe return of Dublin...
that kinda sounds like
a kidnapping, doesn't it?
Doesn't mean it's a kidnapping.
Doesn't mean he's not dead.
Is this a serious theory
or is this your revenge?
"This was sent
from a throwaway phone."
"Do exactly as instructed
or H.D. gets his throat cut"
"and we send you his tongue."
"We want a million dollars
in used 50s and 100s"
"at 0600 tomorrow."
"Location will follow.
No police, or H.D. is dead."
- Any proof of life?
- No.
Huh.
Do not say anything bad
to Mrs. Dublin.
That is an order.
"Jawohl, mein Kommandant."
- Can I see?
- Yeah.
Where is Mrs. Dublin?
Yeah, she cries a lot.
Then she has to freshen her makeup
and then she cries again.
Sort of a cycle.
Three deliberate misspellings
and an obvious military lilt
which suggests
that the writer is not a veteran
but wants us to believe
that he or she is...
so a notch or two less clever
than he or she thinks that they are
using this crime to express some
kind of deep, personal grudge.
The violence
is authentic enough.
Oh, my lord. What now?
What's happened?
It's nothing, Giselle.
These are my colleagues.
Please remain calm.
How can I remain calm?
I can't raise
a million dollars by tomorrow!
We aren't nearly as rich
as people think.
Wh-what do I do?
I can't speak
to the financial aspects, ma'am.
That's your call.
Now can you think of anybody
who may have had a personal grudge
against your husband?
No. Nobody.
My husband is a respected and beloved
member of Sacramento society.
And you?
Do you respect and belove him?
Of course I do.
Deeply. What a question.
Well, wh-why don't you wanna raise
a million dollars to save his life?
Why do you ask that? I do!
Well, the watch and the earrings...
that's, like, a quarter mill right there.
You can raise the money.
You're conflicted because you don't
know if you want your husband back.
You don't like your husband
very much at all.
You're actually a very good actress
playing the part of the loving wife.
That's what I think you are.
Can you look at me
and tell me that I'm wrong?
Duh.
Of course I don't like him
very much.
Everybody in the know
knows that Harvey Dublin
is a mean, lying, backstabbing
crooked son of a bitch.
But I'm his wife and what am I supposed
to do but act like I love him?
Why didn't you leave him?
Have you ever divorced
a mean lawyer?
He has no record of any
personal wrongdoing.
He's a respected lobbyist.
An extortionist and con man
more like it.
So there are a lotta people who may
have wanted to harm your husband.
Are you kidding?
There's people all over the city
praying that he stays gone.
How about you?
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
Oh, I'll raise the money.
I owe him that much.
I knew what I was marrying.
Yes, Mr. Dublin is the target
of some lawsuits.
Most prominent men are at one point
or another in their careers.
It's a hazard of modern life.
So Harvey Dublin's a saint.
That's your position?
No, Harvey Dublin
is not a saint
but I'm his lawyer
and I speak for him.
Look, Harvey started
with less than nothing.
He was a street kid.
His parents were drug addicts.
He lives in fear of falling back
into that world
so maybe he pushes
a little bit too hard.
Maybe he's just a little bit
too intense in his desire to win.
This is America.
That's no crime.
Seven lawsuits pending.
Look, anyone can get sued.
It doesn't mean a thing.
Half the players in this town
are in bed with Dublin
one way or another.
In fact, your, uh, your new director
Gale Bertram...
he's one of his codefendants.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Bank of Claremont vs. Brixham Lake
Development Corporation and others.
- It's gonna be a blockbuster.
- Do go on.
It's a complex land-water
rights thing. It'll run for years.
The point is, Bertram
was named codefendant
to put pressure on the defense
to settle early.
Happens all the time.
Hmm. That's interesting about Bertram.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is.
Who's to gain the most legally speaking
if Mr. Dublin doesn't return?
Well, that's, uh,
that's hard to say.
Too many variables
in the equation.
But he is coming back, right?
I mean, if Giselle pays the kidnappers
why shouldn't he?
Well, stuff happens.
Uh, did you ever serve
in the military, Mr. Colman?
No, I didn't have that honor.
Why do you ask?
Standard question.
Don't just...
Oh, shoot.
Hey, lady, wait up.
Ma'am, we just wanna talk.
- Blah, blah, blah, blah.
- Yeah, blah, blah, blah.
Listen, did you hear about that guy
that was kidnapped
up the street a couple blocks over?
- His driver was shot dead.
- Oh, that. Yeah. Isn't that wild?
- Everybody's talking about it.
- What exactly are people saying?
All kinds of stuff.
Friend of mine said she was there.
- Oh, yeah?
- Well, she's acting all mysterious
like, "I can't tell you
what happened"
- like she's a secret agent or whatnot.
- What's your friend's name?
Yours for 50.
This is a murder investigation.
We could take you in
right now for obstruction.
Oh, baby, save yourself time
and paperwork.
I got 40... 43 bucks.
- Twelve cents.
- Money's tight all over, huh?
Come on.
Cut us a break here.
Sugar... big old tall girl, pink hair.
She'll be around tomorrow night.
Nice doin' business with ya.
- Twelve cents? Seriously?
- What? She cleaned me out.
Twelve cents.
Ah.
Interesting about Bertram, huh?
You said that before.
No, it's not.
I got a weird vibe
the first moment I met him.
Uh, the director
of the division of law enforcement
did not kidnap Harvey Dublin.
So you think.
How well do you know him?
This is your revenge, isn't it?
Well, I-I am simply
gonna ignore you.
I'm not punishing you
though you do deserve it.
Dublin turned out to be
the sleazebag I guessed he was.
He deserves justice
like everybody else.
Oh, you're a cop.
You have to say that.
- You don't really believe it.
- My fingers are in my ears.
Morning!
Hey!
What's happening?
- Nothing yet.
- No kidding. Where's the money?
Trash can down there.
- There?
- Yeah.
Oh. Just as I thought.
No one's gonna show up.
Look at this place. It's far too open
for a ransom drop.
Well, they said no police
and maybe they're stupid enough
to think that there's no police.
They killed a guy
in the street.
They have to know
the police are involved.
They never intended
to pick up the ransom.
Well, my hunch is correct.
The kidnapping's a sham.
Dublin's already dead.
What would be the reason
for a pretend kidnapping?
Well, that is the salient question, yes.
But you can stop wasting
your time here, certainly.
Hey, did Mrs. Dublin use
real money or fake money?
- Real.
- Did you look at it?
No. What would that matter now?
Well, it doesn't matter.
I'm... you know, I'm just a little curious.
What you're saying might be true
and it might not be.
We still have to sit
on this thing for a little while
to make sure nobody
shows up... couple of hours.
- Well, that's just silly.
- It's not silly. It's professional.
Professional shmuh-essional.
- Hey!
- Jane!
Hey, it's real!
Police! Freeze!
Hands in the air!
Get on your knees!
Do it now! Do it now!
It's okay.
Don't move.
"The director is expecting a full
but concise progress report."
- How's that jacket smell?
- This is a different suit.
Yeah, but the other one's ruined,
isn't it?
Power of suggestion.
Okay, you know what?
Bite me.
So...
- Poor Harvey Dublin, huh?
- Sir, no one picked up the ransom drop
so for that and other reasons
we believe that the kidnapping aspect
of this case is a pretense.
- Masking what?
- That we can't say for sure.
We have promising leads.
Well, I need something to tell
the media.
Tell 'em Harvey Dublin's dead.
Well, I'm so glad you decided
to work on this case, Mr. Jane.
Your directness is bracing.
Of course, procedurally
we're still assuming he's alive
until we have proof
positive otherwise.
Why kill Dublin?
Wh-what's the motive?
Well, two possibilities.
Uh, one... simple robbery.
The culprit was going
after the diamond
that, uh,
Dublin always carries on him.
Diamond? What diamond?
Well, apparently Dublin had a terror
of falling back into poverty
of, uh, dying in a pauper's grave
like his father did
so he always carried
a large diamond with him
just in case.
It's kind of a touching story, isn't it?
So someone staged
this abduction
to steal the diamond.
- Okay. Um, where's your evidence for this?
- Well, no actual evidence.
- That's... that's word on the street.
- It's more like a theory, really.
- Word on the street.
- Jane.
So you have nothing?
You... you said
there were two possibilities?
Oh, the other reason
someone would kill him
is uh... b-b-b-Brixham Lake.
- Uh, wait a second.
- What about Brixham Lake?
Well, it's such a complex little scandal
isn't it?
And it all goes away
if Harvey Dublin is dead.
I am a named codefendant
in one of the Brixham Lake lawsuits.
Yes, I saw that.
Very interesting.
Uh, obviously you're innocent
but, uh, I imagine
that there's a lot of stuff
that you would rather
remain secret
that will come out
if the suit goes to trial.
You had ample motive.
So that's option two?
Me? I'm your suspect?
Wha... What are you playing at?
Well, I w... I was just wondering
why you didn't tell us
this guy was such a sleazebag
and that you are up to your neck
in his grubby business.
That's enough.
Yes, it is.
I don't have time for this.
You shall just have to trust
in my innocence, Mr. Jane.
I'm not good at trust.
I'm really trying
to allow you the latitude
that your rare talents deserve
but you make it very difficult.
You two may go now.
- Hightower, stay.
- Yes, sir.
What the hell was that?
Are you insane?
And where did you come up
with that stupid-ass diamond story?
I don't know what came over me.
I see that man, I get
an immediate urge to wind him up.
- He's the director.
- I'm sorry.
He amuses me.
I'm glad he entertains you because
he's gonna fire you now probably.
No. You guys need me
too much.
I'll catch up.
Excuse me?
What did you tell her?
I was complimenting her
on her jacket.
- It's such a vivid color.
- Liar.
You're gonna call me a liar?
- Oh, I hate you. I do.
- Oh.
We have our best people
on this thing 24/7.
I want to extend my sympathies
to the family of Peter Russo
and... and please join us
in our prayers
for Mr. Dublin's safety.
- Are there questions... briefly, please?
- Yeah.
Are you looking into this being
a sex-related crime maybe?
- I mean, that alleyway is...
- No, there's no sex angle, Jeff...
none that we're aware of.
Sir, do you think there's
a Brixham Lake connection here?
No. I don't think so.
But both you and Dublin are involved
in that case, aren't you?
No, no, no.
Wh-what we're thinking
is it seems
that Mr. Dublin was rumored
to keep a large diamond
with him, on... on his person
and the theft of that diamond
is our current line of thinking
as to motive.
- "What kind of diamond is it?"
- "Uh, big."
"It's 2 or 3 carats, I think."
"Why would he carry a diamond
like that around with him?"
"Well, that's a good question, Jeff."
"Uh, perhaps Mr. Dublin
was trying to be prepared"
"for any circumstance.
You know..."
"Understandable, isn't it?
I mean he's, uh, had a tough..."
"Ask just one more question..."
How do you think
the director is going to feel
when he finds out
you fooled him
into talking complete garbage on TV?
It's not garbage
and he'll be very angry
or very happy
depending on
whether I'm right or not.
Right about what?
There is no diamond...
I see. A trap.
Very clever.
- A trap for who?
- Guess.
- Just tell me.
You know what? Screw you.
You crossed a line already
and now you're playing
guessing games with me?
No, it's just
that I'm not sure myself.
- I have a plan, though.
- Oh, sheepdip.
You are still trying to punish me
for lying to you.
Well, you know what?
I'm sorry. Sorry.
You wanted off this case.
You're off.
You can take a nap
in your thinking room.
We'll solve this case
without you, the right way...
with good, solid detective work.
So I take it you don't wanna
hear my plan?
"No, I don't wanna
hear your plan."
"Sheepdip your plan."
Hi.
Hi, ladies.
We're looking for Sugar.
No Sugar. Just Candy.
You're not Sugar?
No, ma'am. Excuse me.
Yeah, well
we kinda think you are.
Yeah, well thinking's free, flaco.
You're gonna need to come
with us, Sugar.
- What for?
- Because you saw what happened
in that alleyway over on Fremont.
Nah, I was just playing.
I didn't see nothing.
- Okay, still.
- Hey!
Let me go!
Okay.
Here.
Thanks.
No problem.
I'm waiting.
Okay.
I'm at the bridge.
Cigarette break.
Limo comes in off Fremont.
I'm about to go over
and talk business
only this pickup truck comes in
behind him and blocks the limo.
I'm thinking, "uh-oh".
So I-I get up out of sight.
And what kinda truck?
It was a truck.
Uh, green or...
or... or brown or blue.
Not... not red.
And, uh, a white guy gets out
and... and says, "Hey".
What'd he look like?
A white guy.
He had a-a black hat on.
- A white guy in a black hat?
- Yeah.
Yeah, and then he...
he walks up to the limo.
The limo driver gets out.
He's like, "Hey, what the hell
are you doing here?"
"Black hat don't say nothing."
"He just pulls out a piece
and boom!"
Shoots the driver three times
and then he walks
over to the limo door
"and drags out this big fat guy."
"Get out", he says.
And then he... he walks him
to the back of the truck
and makes him climb in the back
and the fat dude's calm.
He's like, "You know,
okay, we can negotiate."
And then boom!
Black hat just...
Shoots him in the head.
"And then he... he puts
a tarp over him"
"and then he jumps back
into his car and he takes off"
"and that's all that happened.
Th-that was it."
Okay.
Do you recognize this guy?
Yeah.
That's the... the fat dude.
- He was dead, you think?
- "Yeah, he's dead."
- So this is about ice?
- Ice? What do you mean?
Well, the TV said that the... the fat dude
had, like a 10-million-dollar diamond.
Yeah, it's a theory.
Um... it's very late.
I w... I wouldn't
intrude like this, uh...
only we have an important lead
perhaps Nadine can help us with.
Oh.
Um, yeah, please, of course.
Thank you.
Um, now you told me
that you and your father
talked about everything
together, yeah?
Yes.
Did you ever talk about his work?
Sometimes. But he never mentioned
a diamond
if that's what you're talking about.
The... wh... diamond?
It said on the news
they were looking for a diamond
Mr. Dublin had with him.
- Uh, yeah, that's... that's just all talk.
- See? I told you.
I mean, there's a diamond all right.
So I hear, anyhow.
Uh, Dublin keeps it hidden
in his false tooth apparently
but nobody knew about it
so I can't see
how anybody could've been
going after it.
No. No, I think this is all connected
to a court case.
Did your dad ever mention
Brixham Lake?
No.
You sure? Brixham Lake.
Think hard.
What about Gale Bertram?
No.
Oh.
Well, that's disappointing.
I was sure...
Oh, well. Uh...
Can't win 'em all.
That's it?
Believe me, uh, I know
it's... it's hard to deal with
but, um...
You know, sometimes
the bad guys just get away.
But you said you'd catch them.
You guaranteed it.
Hey, Lisbon.
How's the detective work doing?
"Eh, doing okay."
Well, I tell you what.
Come over and meet me
at Nadine Russo's house
and I'll show you
something exciting.
Lisbon?
You there?
- Hi.
I'm very impressed.
Proud and impressed.
You got the right answer.
No real proof, I expect.
Just guessing, huh?
Hmm. "Kettle to pot.
Hello. Come in, pot."
We have a witness who saw
a white male in a truck
who seemed to recognize
Pete Russo.
- Guesswork.
- Do you have proof?
Relax, wait a while and, uh, we shall
soon be taken directly
to the proof you seek.
Keith, stop!
About six months ago
Nadine was...
staying out past curfew
drinking and smoking...
your basic teenage stuff.
So we had a big conversation
about the rules
and... and things got a little heated
you know, as they do.
Yes.
Look, I felt that
she was over-the-line rude
to her mother and me
and I slapped her.
I'm not proud of it.
But it-it was a tap.
Really.
It was no big deal.
Anyway, Nadine told Pete
about it.
He got mad.
Pete and I were buddies.
You know, we could've had a beer
and a discussion
and we could've worked it out.
No, but he comes
into my house...
"And I don't even have a chance
to defend myself!"
"And he sucker punches me"
"and he beat me up badly"
"in front of my wife
and my stepdaughter."
"Put his foot on my neck
and he spat on me..."
- In my own house!
- That's not right.
Even afterwards, I-I...
it's like I'm the one to blame.
You know, Patricia insisted that we make
peace for Nadine's sake.
He does that to me, and I'm
supposed to just swallow it?
Nobody would.
Oh, I thought about ways
to pay him back.
Oh, I thought about it a lot.
But I knew that if I killed him...
Patricia would guess
that it was me.
Unless I could make his death
look like it was just...
a tragic accident.
Sugar?
No, thank you.
- Okay. There you go.
- Thank you.
My pleasure.
We're very sorry
things worked out this way.
You said you'd find out who did it
and you did.
How did you know?
Uh, well, I...
I kinda knew from the first moment
I met you and Keith.
Those little round glasses
with the muscles...
it just didn't seem to match.
Um, indicated
a deeply conflicted personality
a lot of anger and frustration.
Probably uses those, um,
wrist-strengthening things, right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, um...
never a good sign in a man
over 20.
Obsessive, arrogant
painstaking, uh, secretive
self-righteous. Yeah.
I could go on.
- Yeah.
- Men, huh?
Knew the whole time
and kept it to yourself, eh?
No. No. I only knew when I read
the ransom demand, to be honest
but you lied to me
so fair's fair.
Look, I promise, I will never
lie to you again.
I lied this one time
because I'm concerned.
You're isolating yourself.
You're pulling away from us
from me and the unit.
- You are.
- No.
You are. It's not good.
Wh-what's going on?
Anybody that gets close to me...
bad things happen to them.
A, that's not true
and B, even if it were
I'm a cop.
- It's our job to be in harm's way.
- You're not listening to me.
We're family. What you're doing
is a kind of betrayal.
A surrender. A defeat.
You're letting Red John win.
Oh, please. Please. Really?
Okay. Enough. All right.
No... no more pulling away.
All right? Here, give me a hug.
You don't mean it.
I can tell.
What do you mean you can tell?
You can't tell.
I don't mean it, but you
can't tell that I don't.
- You're guessing.
- Yes, I can tell.
- How?
- I don't know.
I can tell when you're lying now.
- No, you can't tell.
- I-I can, too.
That's nonsense. You're lying.
Liar, liar, pants on fire.
- I'm not lying.
- You are.